There once
was a peculiar doctor,
known for
his extraordinary ability.
He could talk to animals.
Dr. Dolittle's reputation
spread far and wide.
Even the Queen of England
called on him.
So grateful for his help,
she gifted him
a wondrous sanctuary
whose doors were open
to all creatures.
His days belonged
to the animals,
but his heart
belonged to one woman,
Lily, the fearless explorer.
They traveled the globe,
going on great adventures.
Defending creatures
who could not defend themselves.
They made
an extraordinary team.
Soon, that team
became a family.
With Lily by his side,
Dolittle never felt more alive.
Until one day,
she left on an adventure.
Lily died at sea.
Heartbroken,
he locked
the gates of the manor
and completely retreated
from the world.
As for me, and the animals
whose lives he'd saved,
we were left to wonder,
could anyone save his?
Until one morning,
a most unlikely creature
found its way
into Dolittle's life.
A very special boy.
In a time where people
thought of animals
only as possessions,
food, or sport,
this boy felt
quite differently.
This way,
me scattered squirrel.
Right.
Junior flushes them.
You shoot them, yeah?
Right.
Good plan, Dad.
Get ready.
Shoulder your gun.
Do I have to, Uncle?
Come on, boy.
Duck! Duck!
Duck, duck, duck!
There, there they go.
Shoot, shoot, shoot.
You got him, you got him, you got him.
Oh, no, I can't!
Shoot,
shoot, shoot.
You can't keep
missing on purpose.
Oh, look.
He hit something this time.
Oh, no.
We have to help him.
Aye.
We never leave
an animal suffering.
Not on our error.
Here you go.
He's a very odd boy.
Follow Poly.
"Home of Dr. John
and Lily Dolittle.
"We treat all animals."
Uh-uh. Follow Poly.
Secret entrance.
Poly? Where'd you go?
Uh...
Good dog.
Big, hairy...
It's not good.
As far as I'm concerned,
I'm the only human here.
Just ignore them.
There's no getting past
a Kalahari snare, Doc.
It's an ingenious design.
I think you just caught
yourself a boy.
Let me see.
Wait. I don't wanna see.
Just make it go away.
Deep breaths, Doc.
Dab-Dab's got your back.
Don't be afraid, John.
It's just a boy.
This is an opportunity.
This is a nightmare!
Pardon me.
Whatever are you
doing up there?
I've come from Buckingham Palace
on urgent business.
Can you tell me if this is
the home of John Dolittle?
Who are you?
You may call me Lady Rose.
And you are?
Stubbins.
Could you
help me down?
This goes
against Dolittle's rules.
Why are humans
against the rules, again?
If you let humans too close,
you'll get hurt
more than you would
if you didn't
let them in at all.
Isn't that right, Doc?
That's enough, everybody.
Back to our routine.
We have a very full day.
John! Pull yourself together.
You can't ignore people
just because they're, eh, people.
What if they need help?
Ooh.
Possum, play dead.
This is ridiculous.
Chee-Chee,
will you answer the door?
You're the only one with arms.
I think chess was
enough pressure for one day.
Chee-Chee boy,
this is what we trained for.
Be brave
and get rid of them.
And don't forget
your mantra.
"I am not
a prisoner of fear"?
You're not a prisoner of fear.
Have you been
here before?
The queen's
told me all about it.
It's a most
unusual place.
I'm prepared
for anything.
Wonderful.
A gorilla
answering the door.
Just as the queen said.
Oh... Wait a minute...
I have an injured squirrel.
I should never
have let you go.
Hello?
Oh, look at you.
Aren't you peculiar,
posing as a twig?
Move, please.
This is my hiding spot.
Not here.
Are you
all right down there?
Yeah. Fine. Go on.
- Dr. Dolittle?
- Yeah, right.
You have been summoned
to Buckingham Palace
by the queen herself.
Whoo-ha.
Go on.
You should know,
she's fallen gravely ill.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
Go on.
Go on and be gone!
I don't care about anyone,
anything, anywhere anymore.
The birds
will show you out.
Right,
everything's tidy.
Lunch will be served
in a minute, now.
Mmm!
Smells lovely, Doc.
Thanks very much.
Hey, Doc,
save some for us this time.
Sorry, Doc.
Guess I'm scared of kids, too.
Don't worry about that.
Come on, let's eat.
I'm going to be offering
today a brothy soup.
You'll never believe
what we caught in the net.
The queen has asked
for you by name, sir.
Are you hard of hearing?
I told you
I'm closed for business.
What business?
Treating humans.
Intruder alert!
Don't worry.
I'm fine.
Well, I'm not.
My house is descending
into chaos.
Is he yours?
I don't own anybody.
Yoshi had an issue
that he came to me with.
He's always cold.
I have
an injured squirrel.
I don't know what to do.
How was he injured?
I...
I shot him.
What? I can't hear you.
But it was an accident.
Of course,
an accidental firing-upon.
Humans never change.
He's very hurt.
Please help him.
Take that...
and this.
I...
I... I...
I'm too beautiful to die.
Yes?
He's with us.
Dab-Dab, Jip.
Light the lamps,
disinfect the surgery.
You will not tend
to a squirrel...
while the Queen of England's
life hangs in the balance.
Oh, you don't know me
very well, do you?
Don't drop him.
We got a code red.
Code red, code red, everybody!
The doctor is back.
Hang on, little buddy.
Whew! I haven't
done this in a while.
Let's get everything
the way Doc likes it.
Don't worry.
We got you, pal.
Right-o, let's save
this squirrel, shall we?
Okay.
When you wake up,
everything'll be fine.
If I die, I swear
I will haunt your house.
Sterilize the scalpels.
Do not lick any instruments.
Patient's condition
has stabilized.
They're understanding him,
and he's understanding them...
in their own languages.
Going through
the left ventricle, it's brilliant.
Wow.
Dab-Dab,
forceps, please.
Here you go.
That's a piece of celery.
Forceps, Dab-Dab.
Oh, sorry. Here you go.
Still celery.
Forcep?
- Carrot, that is.
- Forcep?
That's a different
piece of celery.
Got it. Forcep.
No, still celery.
Never mind, I'll get it myself.
I wanna know
how to talk to the animals.
Chee-Chee, brow.
My brow as well,
when you've got a second.
Right. Sorry.
I'm going to come here
and be Dolittle's apprentice.
Her Majesty has designated
this land a nature preserve.
If she dies,
the deed will be
owned by the Treasury,
and this place goes away.
- Shut down?
- Mm-hmm.
There you are.
- Whoo, still got it, Doc!
- Phew.
Ooh, whoa.
Ah. There, Cheech.
That's the spot.
Keep an eye on Kevin,
shall we?
He may be prickly
when the anesthetic wears off.
Revenge.
Okay, okay,
enough with the pampering.
You need to go
and help the queen.
There are things
I no longer do.
Work with humans,
or leave the house.
- Or bathe.
- Oh, exercise.
Express emotional
vulnerability.
Wake up, John.
If the queen dies,
the Treasury takes the deed,
and we lose this house.
You're talking out
of your tail feathers, Poly.
The deed was for life.
The last time I checked,
I was very much alive.
The queen's life, John.
Not yours.
Look at that! It just rolls
off my back.
I knew I shouldn't have let monkeys
proofread the contract.
Elliot, Elsie,
you are fired!
It gets worse.
We'll be thrown out
of these gates
right in the middle
of hunting season!
- What?
- No, no, no.
Breathe, Chee-Chee.
We get kicked out
if the queen dies?
We're gonna
be hunted!
Everybody, calm down.
Look at the state
of him now. Hmm!
Fear not, I have an in
at, uh, Regent's Park Zoo.
Everyone, pack your bags!
Uh-uh.
You help the queen,
or we are leaving.
You're bluffing.
Don't make me count.
One...
Three!
...two...
All right! I'll do it.
Marvelous.
Right, let's get you
ready to go, honey.
- I'll go as I am.
- Not looking like that.
- Just grab my doctor's bag.
- Get him.
- Apologies, Doc.
- Hold still, now.
Take your paws off me!
This isn't gonna hurt a bit.
Let's clean him up.
How dare you?
Oh, hey, guys.
Arthur? How long have
you been living in there?
I don't know.
What year is it?
Dab-Dab's got the razor.
That's still celery.
Nighty-night, Doc.
Dolittle used to travel
all around the world.
Look.
Ah. Rummaging through
my private projects, is it?
How is he?
Well, first things first,
the squirrel's name is Kevin.
Expect a full recovery.
And after some violent grooming,
it's been decided.
We will accompany you
to Buckingham Palace, after all.
Hmm. You are going back
to whatever burrow you emerged from.
Try not to shoot anything
on your way home.
Maybe I should stay here.
I don't do well in crowds.
We'll look
after you, Cheech.
But we all go together,
just like the old days.
Ooh, don't forget
Doc's forceps.
That's a leek, Dab-Dab.
Sure, it is.
Styx?
No.
Where are you? Oh.
So, would you care
to come along?
I know.
I had other plans,
as well.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Shh.
Prepare my ride!
Ah, today's gonna
be a good day.
I'm gonna do nothing.
Just prance around,
think my own thoughts,
and... Oh.
He's walking this way,
not a great sign.
He's got no beard.
He looks motivated.
- No. Plimpton, don't be alarmed.
- Ahh.
People only say that when they're
about to be alarming.
- Look, I know it's been a while.
- Sorry about this.
And sorry about that!
All right.
I'm unavailable. Ahh!
Unavailable for the man
who changed your life?
We're going to save
the queen, bro!
I am not your bro.
You should be
an Eskimo's rug by now.
- Ow. Claws!
- Ow. Beak!
- Claws.
- Beak.
Now, now, gentlemen.
Oh, you've gained weight.
Why are you riding me? There's, like,
four horses in front of us.
Cheer up, angry bird.
Kick back and enjoy the ride.
I am the ride.
Buckingham Palace!
We've hit the big time!
Full speed
no longer required!
Whoa.
Welcome home, milady.
Guards! Guards!
Your Ladyship, Rose.
They are
the queen's own guests.
Treat them accordingly.
You better
give us a wide berth!
Make way, boys!
Plimpton!
Don't! Stop!
Don't stop?
Odd decision, but...
Stop! Whoa!
Ahh! Can't see!
Oh, my God!
Okay.
I blame the hat.
Dr. Müdfly.
Lord Badgley.
My Lord.
I come from
the House of Lords.
There is great concern
for Her Majesty's health.
I shall continue to leech
to circulate the vapors
in the bloodstream.
She'll be lucky
to last the week.
This is not the first time
Dr. Dolittle's been here.
You got a dying queen?
Not for long.
Dr. Dolittle
is in the...
Oh, oh. Wait!
Wait for me!
A stowaway,
my lady
who claims to be...
Dr. Dolittle's apprentice!
It's quite all right, Gareth.
Well,
if he was my apprentice,
he should fetch my bags
and keep his gob shut.
I say! Unheard of!
What on Earth?
Animals in
the queen's chamber?
I demand
their immediate removal.
Ah, Lady Rose. My apologies.
Please forgive me.
I didn't realize
that you were part of...
John Dolittle?
Is that Blaine?
Blair.
Poopfling?
- No.
- It was Mudflap?
- No, it's Müdfly.
- Müdfly.
- With an umlaut.
- Yes.
- From the German.
- Of course. From the Germans.
Why is he here?
Her Majesty has personally
requested Dr. Dolittle.
Well, then,
let's get to work.
All right, Jip,
give her a good sniff.
That dog
is licking the queen.
This is outrageous.
Oh, bark.
You all right, fellow?
Something smelled wrong.
And that's coming from a guy
who loves the smell of butts.
Oh, you do love butt.
I detected a whiff
of something else.
Floral, with earthy...
I'm perplexed, Doc. I've never
smelled anything like it before.
Uh, clearly,
Jipsy and I are out of our depths.
May we consult?
Well, of course. I'd be more
than happy to help illuminate...
John and I were students
at Edinburgh years ago.
Some thought he had
a gift for observation.
Ugh.
Oh. Sorry about that, Mini.
Stay here.
Dab-Dab,
clear out the humans.
Boyo, fetch the Botanical Index
and the tea tin.
Everyone out!
Do you understand the words
coming out of my bill?
What do you smell, Jip?
Elderberries?
Hemlock?
Negative.
Aye, aye.
What have you found,
Dolittle?
Well, quite possibly
the answer to everything.
Exposure to toxins...
God, he was
like this at school.
"Lean in, lean in, I'm saying
something interesting."
I am interested.
The queen's symptoms
are due to
the effect
of a rare Sumatran plant...
known as
the Nightshade flower.
A solar eclipse will occur
on the 17th of this very month.
If she has not received the antidote
by then, she will perish.
Is that a Turner?
Must be.
What a fine painting.
I say, Dolittle,
what is your plan?
The plan?
I suppose we do need one.
Well, the queen's only hope is
a cure that's never been tested
from a tree
that's never been seen,
on an island
that's never been found.
Sounds ridiculous, saying it out loud.
But regardless of that,
we have no choice but to embark
on this perilous journey
to obtain the fruit
of the Eden Tree.
What?
Eden Tree.
Oh, my. Fantastic.
The Dolittles with
their Eden Tree Island.
Isn't it enough
that your wife...
Shut up, Blair!
Sorry,
I meant to say,
"Lovely to see you
again, Blair."
We're off now.
Ta-ra.
Oh, its fruit is said
to cure every malady known to man.
Grant eternal life,
even restore the hair
on your head.
You must let nothing
pass her lips
that hasn't been made
and served by you.
Clear?
Yes, I'll see to it.
That's us
to the carriage.
Jip, you need to stay behind
and guard the queen.
Very important.
Right, guard dog mode.
Stand back, everyone,
while I secure the perimeter.
Excuse me.
I do so admire
how you don't give up.
The queen is counting
on both of you.
Good luck.
Right, chop-chop.
We got a long voyage
in front of us,
and the boat isn't
gonna sail itself.
Deep breath, Yoshi.
We haven't got all day.
Seems like
she's full up.
Maybe we could
squeeze in one more.
Plenty of room.
Oh, no.
Uh, Plimpton,
I mean, one more stop,
good fellow.
I can't hear you
because I am not here.
Well, I believe it's time to go
our separate ways.
Uh, I'm going with you.
Certainly not.
It's far
too treacherous.
I'm your apprentice.
You? No, no, no.
Oh, you have
an apprentice?
You don't need an apprentice
and an ostrich.
I'll go home.
I didn't want
to be embarrassed,
so I pretended
you belonged.
I was helpful in there,
wasn't I?
- Hmm.
- The animals like me.
I don't take up much space.
I think I belong here.
Don't make me go home.
Please.
What is that around
your neck? Come on.
I'm worried about
the boy, Bethan.
Give him time.
Time is all.
We're hunters, Bethan.
Hunters!
It has a certain...
We hunt things.
He frees things.
The rabbits and mice.
He carries spiders outside.
Nobody likes spiders.
Not even spiders.
I don't know how your sister
put up with him.
Ugh.
Poly?
What are you doing here?
Making sure
you don't miss the boat.
Am I talking
to an animal?
- Just like Dolittle?
- Oh, no.
I'm speaking human, better than
any parrot ever has actually.
Now, let's pack some clothes.
Come on.
But Dolittle said
I belong here.
Little help, Tutu?
Well, I never heard
him say anything of the sort.
There's something
special about you, Stubbins.
Something I've only seen
in two other humans.
You belong
with us, kid.
And you let me worry about Dolittle.
That's my job.
So, are you ready
for the adventure of a lifetime?
I'm in.
Of course you are.
Poly, let's move.
We got a boat to catch,
and we're burning daylight.
Fret not, ma chérie.
We have the perfect plan.
Ahh!
New plan! New plan!
Come on!
Don't let them get away!
Why are they chasing us?
We're not criminals.
Speak for yourself!
We're wanted in three forests!
And it's not an escape mission
unless you're being chased.
That tickles!
Which way, Tutu?
Down!
Clear the way!
Hey! This way!
Get off the road,
ma chérie!
See you later, suckers.
Whew! We've done it!
We've done it! We've...
...missed it.
Okay, boss,
what's our next move?
We cut our losses.
Change our identities.
Ditch the kid
in the river.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Easy.
What about that bridge?
Yes, the bridge.
Uh, that was
my next suggestion.
Let's go!
Come on, Doc!
At least get out of the hammock!
Your seasickness
will wear off.
Try some
of this ginger root.
You'll get your sea legs back.
You look terrible.
Ah, button it!
Who put me in this hammock?
I am the captain
of this ship, right?
Raise the blasted sails,
will you?
Uh, that's a big bite.
Everyone, look!
Is that the boy?
He's coming to finish the job!
He won't rest
till I'm dead!
He's obsessed!
John,
slow the boat down.
No, I want
to go faster.
Sorry, kid.
Doc says no.
We're going to miss
all the good current!
- I hope you make it.
- Me, too, Dabs!
All right, Bets,
moment of truth.
Whoa. Big hole!
12 o'clock!
Maybe this was
a bad idea.
Let's go, Stubbins,
let's go.
Come on, kid.
Get on the boat!
I've run
out of track!
But not courage!
Fly and be free!
Whoa!
- Whoo!
- Is that thing up to code?
Whoa. Whoa!
No! Oh, no!
Jump, murderer!
You got this.
Oh, I can't look.
No, no, no!
Whoa!
Do it again!
Do it again! Do it again! Do it again!
Yes!
Crushed it, kid.
You made it.
Why y'all cheering
for the kid who shot me?
Ah, he's all right!
Darling.
Can I have a word, please?
Glad you came around
and saw things my way...
What is she thinking?
The boy nearly killed himself.
Oi! This is my ship, right?
And I'm its sovereign.
And there are consequences...
"...to ignoring me." Is that
what you were going to say?
No, no.
Don't mince my words.
And stop messing
with my routine.
Look at the state of you.
You're sick as a dog.
Actually, I have my medicine.
See? This licorice root
is working a treat.
Sit down, John.
Don't embarrass me
in front of the crew.
I'm sparing you
embarrassment.
You need a trim.
All right, all right,
be quick.
It's important to maintain
my status, yeah?
This ship is dangerous,
no place for a... Ow.
- Ow!
- What?
Hurts, man!
Private conversation!
- Okay.
- Sorry.
I know this particular voyage
is hard for you, John.
It is for me, too.
I brought you Lily
just when you needed her,
and now you need
one of your own kind again.
Someone without
feathers or fur.
Fine, the boy can stay,
but it will be on my terms.
And I'll keep
him quite busy.
You'll do it with
a smile on your face.
Crew!
Seems you got
a new shipmate.
As I just told Poly, we are
a bit shorthanded after all, so...
You won't regret it.
Welcome aboard!
I hear you could be a big help
by cleaning this up.
That, too,
if you wouldn't mind.
Oops! Those as well.
And that.
I got these.
Careful with
that medical equipment!
Because a parrot's
in charge of my ship! Brilliant!
He's absolutely thrilled
to have you.
Hmm.
Hello there, little squid.
You don't understand me,
do you?
That would be preposterous.
- Müdfly...
- I wasn't talking to the squid!
I'm dispatching a frigate,
the Britannia,
to follow Dolittle.
But you must not support him
in his foolishness, my lord.
England has
enemies everywhere
waiting for the slightest
sign of weakness.
Entrusting beloved Britain
to a child queen...
That is lunacy.
So, while I remain here,
ensuring no one prevents me
from taking the throne,
you will be on the Britannia,
making certain
Dolittle never returns.
Right.
Round two, yeah?
You got me on the ropes,
you have, Cheech.
Come on. One-two.
Jab, jab cross.
The best form
of defense is attack.
I really don't
wanna fight you.
We're not fighting, are we?
It's a therapeutic session.
I think I'm getting this.
I'm actually starting
to understand.
Stop worrying, John.
Every step is planned out
in my journal.
I'll be back before
you even miss me.
Are you all right?
I think I'm beginning
to understand
a little bit of what
the animals are saying.
Seems you are, boyo.
What kind of polar bear
works on their tan?
Well, what kind
of a bird...
- Wait, are you even a bird?
- Of course I am.
- Well, can you fly?
- No.
- Can you swim?
- Well, what can you do?
- I can run.
I can run.
What bird stuff can you do?
Well, what bear stuff
can you do?
You win this round.
Ro... Roar!
Pickles?
Oh, you were saying "warship"!
Weird time to be
asking for pickles.
I mean, who could eat
when we're under attack?
Enemy! Starboard aft.
Elliot, you and Elsie
ready the machine.
We're gonna need speed.
Send out the call!
Which way
are the lifeboats?
- Mini! Mind the lookout.
- This whole thing is a death boat.
Stubbins, boy,
I need you now more than ever.
To stand still.
Ahh! I surrender!
We surrender!
Oh, hello, Blair,
you chinless wonder.
He said something about
my chin, didn't he?
It's a magnificent chin, sir.
We're in their sights.
Cannons are taking aim.
Let's turn this ship!
I'm on my way!
It is time for me to slip
into something less comfortable.
Hello!
I bought a front-row seat
to crazy town.
Once Humphrey's been secured,
you pull me out on Yoshi's signal.
Me? I can't handle
that type of pressure, Doc.
I'm a cheer-quietly-from-
the-sidelines kind of gorilla.
Don't worry, Cheech.
You'll rise to the occasion. Huh?
You're stronger
than you know.
Now, remember,
courage is not the absence of fear,
but it's...
Wait! You got cut off!
I can't hear you!
I need the second part!
- No time, Cheech. Let's go.
- Oh.
Look, look, they're
already abandoning ship.
Boom!
Oh, this is gonna be cold.
But I'm coming in hot!
Humphrey here.
Let's hook it up!
Where we headed?
South!
Okay, I can do this.
I can do this.
Full steam ahead!
Go, Humphrey, go!
Are they pulling away?
- Do it, whale, do it.
- Whoo-hoo!
It's working!
How is this possible?
Well, sir, it appears Dolittle and
a polar bear have harnessed a whale...
It was a rhetorical question!
Just fire!
I dropped the rope!
I failed. I knew
I couldn't do it.
Yoshi!
Hang on. I'm coming, kid!
- No, no, no!
- You're doing great!
Oh, this is gonna
murder my back.
Quit complaining,
you oversized flamingo.
- Oh, no, no, no!
- Oh, no.
Oh, no.
Oh, yes!
I let you down, Doc.
Look at me, I'm fine.
We're all fine.
- I froze.
- No, no, no, Cheech.
It's okay to be scared.
Mm-mm.
You saved me, did you?
Fair play.
Thanks very much.
Well done, everybody.
Feel like
you belong now, kid?
I guess I do.
We lost him.
- I guess I do.
- Great work, gang.
Eat our dust,
Müdfly!
They've gotten away, sir.
Oh, really? I thought
they disappeared into thin air.
I'm afraid not, sir.
They've escaped.
Read the room, Lieutenant.
I can see they've escaped.
But not for long.
It's a miracle.
That must mean
I am the Chosen One.
I'm gonna change the...
Whale power.
Dolittle had to write
a paper about it,
which of course
nobody took seriously.
This one even theorizes
the existence of dragons.
Just preposterous.
Sir, I'm afraid
your obsession with Dolittle is...
What obsession?
I'm not obsessed
with Dolittle.
You're obsessed
You're the one obsessing
about my obsession with...
I'm loath to admit it,
but he's more valuable alive,
for now.
But, luckily,
I think I know
where he's going.
Kevin's log, day seven.
I'm now totally isolated.
The enemy has
ingratiated himself
with the captain and crew.
No sign of promised tropical island
or the magic fruit.
But I will endure.
Take the wheel, Stubbins.
- Really?
- Yeah, yeah.
I have to calculate
our route coordinates.
The bees are buzzing
about you.
Seems you are getting a rudimentary
grasp of their language.
Thirty-five degrees portside.
Well...
I have noticed when they fly
in a zig-zag pattern,
they sort of go...
Which means,
"Back off, kid."
But when Dab-Dab goes...
That means,
"Look at this."
Mm. "Look at me."
- Oh, close.
- Not bad, though.
Oh. No, when
Chee-Chee says...
When Chee-Chee says...
That means,
"Where's my blanket?"
Very good.
Is that the map
of Eden Tree Island?
The Eden Tree
cannot be found on any map.
And to call it an island is
to suggest that it is of our world,
and it is anything but.
That is why we must first
go to Monteverde,
birthplace of the only person
to ever chart a course to the tree.
Her name was Lily. She wrote
the route in a journal.
But on her voyage,
she was shipwrecked.
The world lost the greatest
explorer I've ever known.
The journal
from that expedition
was all that survived.
Elliot, Elsie, do you mind?
So, anyway,
you get the picture.
To have any chance
of finding the tree,
we have to go to Monteverde
and steal that flipping journal.
Steal the journal?
Did I say that?
Well, what's the worst
that can happen?
Don't worry, I know an omen when I see one,
and that was not an omen.
Stealing the journal
is not a big deal!
In fact, Monteverde itself
is not a big deal.
The stop at Monteverde
was a very big deal.
After all, this island
of bandits and thieves
was once a place Dolittle,
Lily, and I called home.
Until the doctor made an enemy
of the island's notorious
ruler, King Rassouli.
And just our luck,
his most prized possession was
the very journal we needed to steal.
So, Dolittle
needed a disguise.
While I was left watching over
the rest of the crew,
Dolittle and Stubbins
snuck into the palace.
I'm about to die!
Once inside, their path ended
at a heavily bolted door, naturally.
But Dolittle still had
questionable contacts
on the island.
Hut, hut, hut.
The opening bid will suffice.
You have my attention.
Don Carpenterino. I'm here
on behalf of these humans.
They will pay you handsomely
for your family's lock-picking skills.
You come to me for this,
on the day of my daughter's wedding?
Wait a minute.
Which daughter?
It's not... Sheila?
My Sheila?
She's getting married?
To a scorpion
named Dylan.
Sorry, Boy Scout. I guess Sheila's
into bad boys now.
We were gonna spend the rest
of our life spans together.
Move on, James.
What's your human's
best offer?
Two more now,
and two later. Huh?
Okay. You have
yourself a deal.
See you around,
Boy Scout.
Guys, I'm no Boy Scout.
Also, what's a scorpion
got that I don't got?
Besides a massive stinger...
Get over her, James.
You dated for two weeks.
These bars are new.
Totally messing up my plan.
I can fit
through them.
No, no, no.
It's too dangerous, man.
Can't go in there
on your own.
Let me
take him in, Doc.
I need something to distract me
from this Sheila reveal.
Are you sure your head's
in the right place, James?
Oh, yeah. I'll get the kid in,
and then fly headfirst into a brick.
Just kidding. I'm fine.
Aye. All right.
James will look after you.
It's fine.
Listen closely. Get the journal
and get out of there.
Go through the room quietly.
Look for the tiger's eye.
Go down the hidden staircase.
And most importantly,
keep your disguise on.
There's just
one little thing you should know.
Rassouli loves
his cats.
But that's
no problem for us,
'cause we can just
fly right over the...
Wait.
Uh, I see the mistake
I made here. You can't fly.
Hey! Oh! Watch out!
Kitty cat on your six.
Oh, God.
Oh! Whoa, whoa!
Hey!
Slick move, kid.
We make
a pretty good team.
A real couple
of bad boys.
Okay, partner. You know where to go.
I'll keep watch
on these lions.
That's what
a bad boy dragonfly does.
Would Dylan
get this close to a lion?
Would he get this close?
How about this close?
Oh...
This is bad.
This is very bad.
"Lily Dolittle"?
We got the journal!
Open up!
Just kidding, he blew it.
- Bye!
- Oh, dear.
Stubbins!
Former resident here.
- Don't move.
- Huh?
Don't touch.
Hmm.
All I wanted was my daughter
to marry wisely,
and instead, I got
the ringleader of a circus.
I never understood
what Lily saw in you.
A common complaint the world over
for fathers of beloved daughters.
But in this instance,
I think we can all agree,
it is particularly accurate.
- Huh...
- Come here.
Come here.
I'm certain you didn't
mean any of that.
It was her journal.
The only thing of hers
my men found in the wreckage.
It belongs here.
All you had to do
was never show your face again
and leave it at that.
You failed.
Now you'll pay
for taking Lily away from me.
You knew what would happen
if you returned.
Yes.
Barry! Barry! Barry!
You should go.
It's my past that's caught up with me,
not yours. Yeah?
But you're my friend.
Go. Don't look back.
You're better off
without him, kid.
Um...
I'm in compliance.
Ho-ho! Yes. Finally,
some action down here.
Boy, was it
getting boring.
You know, Doc,
I hate to tell you,
but you're going down,
my friend.
You'd do well to keep
your buckteeth together.
What is that smell?
Hey, fellas, I think Dr. Dolittle
did a little doo-doo.
Did Dr. Dolittle
do a little doo-doo?
Perhaps
when I'm out of here,
I'll teach you some manners
and accept your lucky foot
as payment.
Oh, this lucky foot?
Don't worry about it, Doc,
'cause both of my lucky feet
are going to be tap dancing
on your grave
when my guy's
done with you!
Taking bets over here!
In the right corner,
wearing golden stripes,
with a sparkling record
of 872 kills,
Barry "The Butcher" Bernstein.
Dr. Dolittle. Remember me,
your old patient?
It's Barry.
Barry. How could
I forget you?
Oh, but you did, Doc.
We were just starting to make progress,
and then you ran off
with Rassouli's daughter
and abandoned me.
Well, uh...
I'm back now.
Er, perhaps we should
just pick up where we left off...
Enjoy the feast!
What will
happen to Dolittle?
Well, he's a dead man.
Yeah.
He'll think he can talk
his way out of it,
but Barry has gone
completely nuts.
But you...
You are one of us now.
To Dolittle's death!
- Psst.
- Hey! It's you!
You made it.
I need you to get
a message to my friends on the boat.
A message? Sure.
When have I ever let you down?
All I hear, day after day,
"Oh, Barry,"
you're such a disappointment.
"Why can't you be
more like your brother?
"He eats poachers
for a living, you know."
Yes, Mother, I know!
The whole jungle knows.
Oh, my head.
Your migraines are brought on
by severe maternal issues
and compounded
by sibling rivalry.
Please make it stop.
Oh, no, no, no.
- Lie down.
- Oh, my head.
We could resume
your treatment.
The stress
is unbearable.
I just want
to be a good boy.
I just want to make
Mummy proud.
There we are.
No one I eat will
ever be good enough.
There's the release.
Release it.
I will never be
good enough.
Unless I eat you!
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
Because every mother wants their son
to grow up and eat a doctor.
You're a sick kitty.
Come here, Doc.
I'll make it quick.
I've got another one
of these in an hour.
Give up, Dolittle.
You can't outsmart...
Oh. What was that?
Oh, wait!
Now it's over there.
And now it's over here.
Now it's back over there.
Got it.
And now it's over here.
Oh, I lost it.
I've got to get it.
A cat
is still a cat.
Easily distracted.
New game, Doc.
Get back down here.
Come on down, Doc!
Okay, James,
you can't let this kid down.
You've gotta deliver
this message.
Oh, no, it's James.
From now on, no more focusing
on relationships and...
Whoa! Poly? Is that you?
- James? James?
- Ooh, your feathers really filled out nice.
James!
What happened, James?
Oh, right! Message.
Huh. My bad.
The kid's been captured
by Rassouli,
and Barry's about to have
Dolittle for lunch.
Looks like we're
going ashore after all.
Be a darling and grab
my dynamite, will you?
We need to split up
if we're going to pull this off.
Chee-Chee,
you're coming with me.
Where are we going?
No, no, no, don't tell me.
Just tell me when we get there.
Yoshi,
create a distraction.
I hope
this is enough.
We are being attacked!
Come on down, Doc.
Therapy's the answer!
Oh, no!
Worse than I expected.
I got you, Doc.
Back off, Barry!
Poly, don't!
An appetizer.
I got you, Poly.
Any final diagnosis, Doc?
Don't you want to be the best Barry
you could be?
I'm about to.
I am not
a prisoner of fear!
I'm not a prisoner
of fear?
Oh, no, no, no.
It's okay to be scared.
Ow, ow.
You should be scared.
It's okay to be scared!
Give him a good hiding.
Okay, we're doing this.
We are doing this!
We're not doing this!
Hit him in the low area!
Down there.
Oof. That's gotta hurt.
Ow, my Barry berries!
That will work.
Cheap shot, ape!
Wait...
I haven't
finished my treatment.
Go to sleep, baby tiger
Time to put those claws away
Anyway...
You need this
more than I do.
Tell me I'm enough,
Mummy.
I had 50 grand
riding on that.
Well,
I won't pay that.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a winner.
Thanks for sticking
with me, Doc.
I have it!
- I have it!
- Stop! Halt!
And now,
I'll have it.
She had
such a sure hand.
Exactly what
the doctor ordered.
What did they offer you,
Müdfly,
to murder
the Queen of England?
Quite a few things, actually.
Knighthood. Windward House.
Chair of the Royal College.
In no particular order.
Oh, and the icing on the madeleine will be
the scientific accolades
that accrue from the proper study
of the Eden Tree.
All thanks
to Lily Dolittle.
Actually, no.
That's still madeleine.
The icing is knowing that
you know I won.
Oh, and, Dolittle, I'm so sorry
for that hole in your boat.
What hole?
Abandon ship!
Everyone, overboard!
Oh. Not good.
Don't look back.
Ahh! Help!
I'm on it, Doc!
I can't fly!
And I can't swim!
Got you, buddy.
Plimpton, I'm not
losing you, bro.
Step away from the light!
There is no light.
I'm alive! I'm alive!
I'm alive,
thanks to you, Yoshi.
You've always
been so kind.
It's difficult to say goodbye.
Please don't say that.
It's all right.
You've done your best.
Your queen is proud.
Where are you, Dolittle?
Hey, big bird,
you doing okay?
No.
Nothing about me
is okay.
My father
was right about me.
I should have
been an omelet.
Pfft. I know how you feel.
My dad said he was going out
for a pack of seals one night
and never came back.
I guess we got something
in common after all, Plimpton.
What is this feeling?
I'm all warm
and fuzzy inside.
That's friendship, bro.
Huh. Not bad,
bro.
I'm not crying,
you're crying.
Right.
Gather round, shall we?
Huh? Let's have a look
where we are now.
That's the spirit, John.
Oh, this is
gonna be good.
I'm already getting
duck bumps.
We are finished.
Is this a pep talk?
'Cause it's a weird one.
I can sniff defeat
like a truffle pig.
This can't
be the end.
Yeah. I smell it.
- We can still save the queen.
- Nope.
- We can still save your house.
- Whoa-uh.
I believe in you.
We can keep going.
Oh, you've got a point there.
Except the journal's gone,
we've no way to find
the Eden Tree,
and our boat is sunk.
He makes a strong argument.
On the plus side,
you are all cured.
Chee-Chee,
you are brave now.
Plimpton and Yoshi
are getting along.
Ow. Remember,
back! Back!
Sort of.
And, Stubbins,
you've made friends,
and you can
even talk to them.
You don't need me.
I'll stay here
and offer medical services to this island
of random bandits and outlaws.
The doctor's here.
Seeking new patients.
Cash only.
Ladies, gentlemen,
who'd like to dance?
I've got a bad case
of dancing fever.
So watch out,
it's infectious.
Cha, cha,
cha, cha, cha, cha.
Can't help him.
That explorer
you told me about,
she would have
never given up.
She was your wife,
wasn't she?
You wanna know
the ironic bit?
I don't know
what "ironic" means.
Irony is when
you find a woman,
and she makes your life more wonderful
than it had any right to be,
and then, poof, she's gone,
and it's all your fault.
This journey was my chance
to finish what she started.
Lily insisted I care
for the animals at home,
so I stayed behind.
Rassouli's right.
I should have been with her.
Now, all I have left of her is
the ghost I see when I hold our rings.
So, you see her, too?
Not only did you lose
my daughter's journal...
...but your polar bear
blew up my village.
We don't know that.
And your gorilla
beat up my tiger.
No good.
Let's go.
Here, stay.
No, no, no.
Mm.
Yeah.
Irony
is me
wanting to kill you
with every fiber
of my being,
but loving
my daughter more.
I miss her, too.
She would have wanted
you to keep going.
So!
Get going,
before I stop
feeling sentimental.
She's saying
we don't have a ship.
Well, uh,
I have
the perfect vessel for you.
Bit of a fixer-upper.
It's got good bones.
At least it floats.
We'll just have to make
the best of it, won't we?
Ooh. Company!
Uh, who's that?
Hi! I'm Jeff.
Crikey.
If Lily's research
was correct,
then Müdfly was well on his way
to Eden Tree Island.
All we needed to do
was track Müdfly.
But how
do we do that?
Whales, boyo.
Whales.
I can't believe
you're flipping him off.
I know.
That man has no chin.
We found him.
Follow us.
Eden Tree Island.
- Whew.
- Oh, wow.
Extraordinary.
This must be it.
The map points us
directly into the center
of this mountain.
Don't look down.
Let's keep our beaks up, shall we?
Trying
to stay positive.
What the heck
are we doing up here?
Going in the back way,
my feathered buddy.
What are you
complaining about?
This is the widest branch
I've ever scurried on.
Don't look down,
look at me.
Whoa. A big cave.
Stay close, keep quiet.
Kevin's log, day 12.
Some force beyond
my comprehension still compels me
to follow this crew of lunatics,
the squirrel killer,
and their deranged leader.
Perhaps it's the magic tree
that draws me.
- Rifle troop!
- Hide. They're close.
- Fall in!
- Turn it down now. Stay down.
Foxfire fungus.
We must be near it now.
Look, Doc.
It's lighting a path
all the way to
the man who wants us dead.
Stay right there.
Go on, then, soldier boy.
Spoil yourself.
Oh.
Hello, Blair.
Looking for a tree,
is it?
Trees don't often
grow in caves.
Didn't you pay attention
in botany class?
No, but pay attention
to this, Dolittle.
I beat you!
You filthy animal...
Move it. Come on, beasts.
...hoarder!
So, where is it?
Where's what?
The Eden Tree.
Truth is,
I haven't got a clue.
Don't be ridiculous,
you're John Dolittle.
You get everything
you want.
Not today, I don't.
You really don't have
any idea, do you?
How does ignorance feel?
Oh.
Well, very freeing, actually.
One must hug uncertainty,
don't you think?
That's how Lily
lived her life.
Embrace the unknown,
and the answers
will be revealed.
You sad, misguided nut,
Dolittle.
Give that to me!
Give me that.
I might find
this damn tree on my own.
And, by God,
history will remember me.
Yeah. Something interesting
going on now.
God, that feels a lot larger
than all of us.
Something's moving!
Look out!
Retreat!
Down over here,
the lot of you! Come on!
Yoshi, stay down!
He saved me.
I have a second chance
to live a life of kindness
and generosity. And...
Take him, not me!
I'm a good person now.
We're gonna make a run for that ditch
while she's distracted...
Yoshi!
- Get this off of me!
- Cheech.
Help me! Plimpton!
I'll save you, bro!
Right. Think fast.
Get this off of me!
This'll likely
upset her a bit.
No! Doc!
- No!
- John!
No!
Dolittle!
Dolittle.
Help!
Is he speaking
dragon?
You may be able
to speak my language,
but that does not make you
worthy of the fruit.
I know protecting the tree
is your duty,
but you won't be able
to continue much longer,
considering the damage
you've taken and the pain you're in.
Oh, you know
nothing of my pain.
But I do.
I've felt it as well.
The kind that doesn't come
from a bullet or a blade,
but cuts much deeper.
And how in every moment and every movement,
you feel that pain again.
Yeah?
It's hard to carry on
when you've lost
the one you love.
Just leave!
Uh,
what just happened?
Oh. Broken hearts.
What the heck
are you doing here?
Don't worry, guys. I got this.
We're both dragons.
Hey, just wondering, you know,
dragon to dragon,
if you wouldn't mind
telling me where... Ow! Ow! Ow!
She's really mad. I'll wait
for whoever survives outside.
John, let's just get out
of here while we still can.
No. I think we're here
to help her.
Yeah.
- We haven't got much time.
- Hmm?
Uh, I imagine
it's a bit tender here?
Oh...
I'm unarmed.
I pose no threat to you.
The emotional stress over the years
has done damage to your stomach.
Get away from me.
You have a severe
impaction of the colon,
and if I don't manually
fragment it, it'll go septic.
You won't be able to protect
anything anymore. Hmm?
Ooh, that sounds like
some tummy ache.
I tell you what,
give us five minutes.
If you don't feel better,
you can fry us all.
Stop talking.
Just get on with it.
We have to get you
on your side.
We need to perform
an emergency extraction.
Extraction? Uh,
what are we pulling out?
- Go get 'em, gang!
- Got your back, Doc.
It's showtime!
Three, two, one...
Turn.
Chee-Chee,
chuck me the forceps.
Knew it would
come in handy. Told ya!
Everybody knows
what to do.
Just breathe.
Works for me.
It's okay, just hold on
to my wing, sweetie.
Dab-Dab's here.
Oi!
You are my apprentice.
You keep her calm.
Did you know that the leek
is the national emblem of Wales?
And very useful it is, too.
You might feel
a bit of pressure.
I got her.
Good heavens!
Oh, no, you didn't.
Oh, my gosh!
Ah, just clearing the way.
Is that armor?
You got the whole
Spanish army in here.
Give us a deep breath.
Hold it.
- Word of warning.
- What's up, Doc?
When removing
the blockage...
Yoshi, now.
...there may be
an initial release of wind.
Ugh!
Respect.
It's all right.
Nobody heard that.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
We all do it.
We're all animals.
I can taste it.
- Okay, I'm back. What did I miss?
- Right.
Oh, my gosh!
This is the big one.
We're in the homestretch now.
Cheech, get behind me.
I'm with you, Doc.
On your call.
Heave!
Oh, it's breaching.
Blood rushing to my head.
Everything turning red.
One last push, madam,
if you please.
Thank you.
We did it!
Teamwork makes
the dream work.
That was a lot,
but we did good.
To put it simply,
more leafy greens
and less armor in your diet.
I've seen armies
of every kind,
but nothing like you.
What unites
such a group of creatures?
Well, we may not
look it, right,
but somehow
we just belong together.
Now let me help you.
Lily would
have loved it, John.
We would never have found it
without her.
Wow.
I just got the chills,
and I'm not
even cold.
Thank you for showing me
the way, my love.
We know, O Lord,
there is no word impossible to thee.
And that, if thou willst,
thou canst yet raise her up
and restore her to
a longer continuance amongst us.
O Father of mercies and the Lord of all,
comfort her health in time of need...
I'm sorry we couldn't
save you, Your Majesty.
...if her disillusion
draweth near.
It is with great sadness...
Wait a minute.
I smell something.
It smells like...
...hope!
...that I have to announce...
...that the queen is no more.
Somebody call a doctor?
My mates!
A very dramatic entrance, boys.
- Well played.
- We've arrived.
Dolittle.
Clear a path. There isn't
a moment to waste.
I have procured that
which is said to not exist.
Behold, the fruit
of the Eden Tree.
I said, clear a path.
Seize them!
Sorry, but... Sorry.
- Go!
- Seize him!
You were born
for this moment.
I born.
Mini, take flight!
Get in!
Go, go, go!
No!
No, no, no!
Kevin's log, day unknown.
The killing has ended.
Let there be life!
Lady Rose,
is there a giraffe
in my bedchamber?
Yes. Oh, yes,
and a polar bear,
and a gorilla,
and a parrot, and a duck.
An ostrich.
Our humble thanks
be to God.
And well done,
Dr. Dolittle.
Not quite done, are we?
Interesting. Carry on,
Styx, I'm all ears.
What's that?
Er, Styx here agreed to stay behind,
keep his 12 eyes on things.
He's just catching me up.
Like all leaf insects,
he speaks in
eight-syllable phrases,
and he states...
"Lord Badgley
did poison the queen."
What? He did?
Really, Dolittle,
this is too much.
You're certain?
Well, this would be the time.
No, I'm sorry.
Styx is quite adamant.
"In his right pocket, the vial."
Ugh, that's only seven.
Oh, in his right pocket.
"The vial of Deathly Nightshade."
Let's have a look,
shall we?
You can't possibly believe that
he's talking to an insect.
Well...
I've spoken to ladybugs,
making a wish before they fly away.
Let's have a look.
Ooh.
No one messes with my family.
Take one more step,
and I'll rip you
a brand-new...
Come on!
Ha!
To the Tower with him.
Ah! Someone's been a bad boy.
Come on.
And I don't know why you're all
standing there.
Nobody's died.
Leave me in peace.
You, too.
Not you, Dr. Dolittle.
A moment,
if you would, please.
Lady Rose, who is this person,
and why is he staring at me?
He's Stubbins.
Uh, I want to be
an animal doctor.
He saved
your life.
Thank you.
It's good to have
you back, Doctor.
Poly?
Anything you'd like
to say to me?
Aye, you were right.
I suppose it is nice to get out
of the house every once in a while.
Stubbins. Mini.
Enough. We have far less
important places to be.
Our story
ends the way it began.
I have a letter for Dr. Dolittle!
Somebody get me down!
Mostly.
There once
was a peculiar doctor...
...who found
he was at his best
when sharing...
...his extraordinary
ability with others.
Excellent.
Soon, Doctor Dolittle
reopened his gates,
as Lily would have wanted.
Three more
in the queue, gang.
Copy that.
Dolittle discovered his place
in the world once again.
After all,
it's only by helping others
that we can truly
help ourselves.
Oh, and in case
you're wondering...
Psst!
You bats.
Show me the way
out of here.
Psst.
You understand me!
No, wait! Wait, wait.
Wait!